<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>news on Ritesh&#39;s Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://blog.rsinha.org/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in news on Ritesh&#39;s Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 22:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.rsinha.org/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>India Graduates Millions, But Too Few Are Fit to Hire via WSJ.com</title>
      <link>https://blog.rsinha.org/posts/india-graduates-millions-but-too-few-are-fit-to-hire-via-wsj-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 22:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rsinha.org/posts/india-graduates-millions-but-too-few-are-fit-to-hire-via-wsj-com/</guid>
      <description>BANGALORE, India—Call-center company 24/7 Customer Pvt. Ltd. is desperate to find new recruits who can answer questions by phone and email. It wants to hire 3,000 people this year. Yet in this country of 1.2 billion people, that is beginning to look like an impossible goal.
So few of the high school and college graduates who come through the door can communicate effectively in English, and so many lack a grasp of educational basics such as reading comprehension, that the company can hire just three out of every 100 applicants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India to set up automatic monitoring of communications</title>
      <link>https://blog.rsinha.org/posts/india-to-set-up-automatic-monitoring-of-communications-privacy-good-gear-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 09:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rsinha.org/posts/india-to-set-up-automatic-monitoring-of-communications-privacy-good-gear-guide/</guid>
      <description>India plans to set up a centralized system to monitor communications on mobile phones, landlines and the Internet in the country, a minister told the Rajya Sabha, the upper house of Parliament, on Thursday.
Indian laws allow the interception and monitoring of communications under certain conditions, including to counter terrorism.
A pilot of the new Centralized Monitoring System (CMS) is to be started by June next year, subject to clearances by other government agencies, Gurudas Kamat, Minister of State for Communications and Information Technology told the Rajya Sabha, according to an announcement by the government&amp;rsquo;s Press Information Bureau.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murderer with &#39;aggression genes&#39; gets sentence cut</title>
      <link>https://blog.rsinha.org/posts/murderer-with-aggression-genes-gets-sentence-cut-life-03-november-2009-new-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2009 05:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rsinha.org/posts/murderer-with-aggression-genes-gets-sentence-cut-life-03-november-2009-new-scientist/</guid>
      <description>In 2007, Abdelmalek Bayout admitted to stabbing and killing a man and received a sentenced of 9 years and 2 months. Last week, _Nature _ reported that Pier Valerio Reinotti, an appeal court judge in Trieste, Italy, cut Bayout&amp;rsquo;s sentence by a year after finding out he has gene variants linked to aggression. Leaving aside the question of whether this link is well enough understood to justify Reinotti&amp;rsquo;s decision, should genes ever be considered a legitimate defence?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
